In the very beginning of the lesson you have already seen this diagram.
在本课程一开始 大家已经见过这张图了
By now you might be able to guess why the Behavior Module
但是现在大家也许已经能猜出来
updates on a lower frequency than for example the Trajectory Module.
为何行为模块相比其他模块具有较低更新频率 比如与轨迹模块相比
This is due to the fact that the high level decisions made in
这是因为在行为模块中 高层次的决策需要消耗更多时间
the behavior module spend a longer time horizon and just don't change as frequently.
而且 这种决策并不会频繁变更
But the Trajectory Module does still count on
但是轨迹模块仍然要依赖于
our decisions and it's important that the over all system architecture
我们做出的决策 此外 重要的是
doesn't allow for a comparatively slow module like
我们的整体系统架构不允许存在一个相对较慢的模块
the behavior planner to clog up the proper functioning of the other faster components.
比如 行为规划器 因为这会阻塞其他较快模块的正确运行
Let's take a second to talk about what's known as
我们花一点时间来讨论所谓的调度问题
a scheduling problem and how it can be handled in the self-driving car.
以及在无人驾驶车上是如何解决此问题的
This diagram shows what happens during two processing cycles of the Behavior Module.
这张图展示了行为模块的两个处理循环之间发生的事情
As you can see, the Prediction Module updates with a higher frequency than Behavior.
正如大家所见 预测模块比行为模块更新更加频繁
Trajectory is even higher. And so on.
轨迹模块比预测模块更新得还要快
But focus your attention on what happens after behavior has completed its first cycle.
但是 大家注意看 当行为模块完成第一次循环后发生的事情
To begin its second cycle,
为了开始第二次循环
the behavior module needs data from prediction and localization.
行为模块需要从预测模块和定位模块获取数据
For localization, it's easy in theory since at
对于定位模块 理论上没什么问题
this instant it will have some fresh data and behavior could just use that.
定位模块此刻将包含一些最新更新数据 行为模块可以直接使用
But what about for prediction.
但是预测模块则不然
It's actually right in the middle of an update cycle at this instant.
此刻 预测模块仍然处于更新循环过程中
Should behavior just wait until prediction is done?
这时候 行为模块会等待预测模块完成循环吗？
No. If we start waiting then we block up the pipeline for downstream components.
答案是 否 因为如果行为模块等待 那么它将阻塞整个循环管线 影响下游模块
The answer is to use data from here and accept that it's a little stale.
正确做法是使用现有数据 并接受这些数据并非最新数据的事实
When you implement your path planner for the final project,
当大家在我们的最终项目中实现你们自己的行为规划器时
we will provide you with the code that handles all of this.
我们会提供相关代码给大家 来处理这种问题
But it's worth mentioning that this is how it's done.
但是 这里还是有必要对此作出解释